uefa.org 2017-06-30

# UEFA Privacy Policy - UEFA.org

**UEFA**  
 **Union des Associations Européennes de Football**  
 **Route de Genève 46**  
 **Case postale**  
 **CH-1260 Nyon 2**  
 **Switzerland**

UEFA takes Your privacy seriously and understands the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of Your personal data and other information stored about You.

UEFA is committed, in the course of its activities and in compliance with the applicable law on data protection, to ensure the confidentiality, integrity and availability of Your personal data, as well as to respect Your privacy. The commitments described in this Privacy Policy fulfil the values, the principles of action and behaviour of UEFA and are established in compliance with Swiss law and more specifically with the Swiss Federal Act of 19 June 1992 on Data Protection.

Please read the following Privacy Policy carefully to learn more about UEFA's processing of Your personal information that UEFA collects when You visit and use the UEFA Platforms.

This Privacy Policy has been drafted in English and has been translated in other languages. In the event of any discrepancy between the English and the translated texts, the English text shall prevail and be used to solve doubts of interpretation.

Date of issue of the latest version of this Privacy Policy: 06/2016

 **What this Privacy Policy covers**  
This Privacy Policy covers UEFA's collecting and processing of personal data that UEFA collects when You are on the UEFA Platforms and when You use Services, as described in Our Terms. This Privacy Policy also covers UEFA's collecting and processing of any personal data that UEFA's business partners share with UEFA unless otherwise stated.

 **The Information We Collect from You**  
UEFA, through the UEFA Platforms, collects and processes Your personal data in order to provide You with a service, and for the purpose of publishing and sharing information plus documents related to football.

Please refer to Our Terms to read and consent to the specific purpose of the UEFA Platform You are using and the exact list of information collected from You. Your data will only be collected and processed under Our Terms.

Once You register with UEFA and access the UEFA Platforms, You are not anonymous to UEFA. You therefore declare having been clearly and specifically informed by the Terms about such processing and the possible disclosure of personal data to third parties and expressly consent to such a use of Your personal data.

 **Automatic Information Collected**  
UEFA also automatically receives and records non-sensitive information on its technical infrastructure logs about Your computer when You visit UEFA Platforms, regardless of whether You have registered for an account or not by just browsing our servers. UEFA may collect, including but not limited to, Your Web browser software, Your internet protocol (IP) address which identifies Your computer, UEFA's cookies, the referring website and the page You requested. UEFA may also collect information about Your location, and Your online activity on the UEFA Platforms.

UEFA uses information collected for three general purposes: for technical administration of the UEFA Platforms, for research and development to achieve and maintain a high service level and for customer information (to customise the content You see, to fulfil Your request for certain products and services and to contact You about specials and new products and services).

 **Information Sharing and Disclosure**  
UEFA will not sell, rent or transfer Your personal data to third parties, such as but not limited to IT service supplier, consultants and any other third party processing personal data on behalf of UEFA, without Your consent and for reasons other consistent with the purpose for which the data were originally collected or for other purposes authorized by law.

However, by approving Our Terms, You expressly give Your consent and agree to the disclosure of Your personal data by UEFA and Your consent is deemed to be given to third parties when:

1\. UEFA needs to send the information to third parties who work on behalf of or for UEFA to provide a product or service You have requested. Unless otherwise stated so, these third parties are prohibited to use the personal data UEFA provides to them beyond what is necessary to provide the product or service to You.

2\. UEFA needs to send the information to the police/state authorities in particular to carry out security or administrative controls in relation to venues or events You have requested access to.

3\. UEFA needs to comply with court or authority orders.

4\. UEFA finds that it is necessary, as determined in UEFA’s sole discretion, to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, emergency situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any persons, violations to Our Terms or as otherwise required by law.

Before disclosing Your personal data to third parties, UEFA will ensure that sufficient security measures and adequate data protection are guaranteed by the third party and take reasonable steps to ensure compliance with those measures.

In particular, UEFA ensures that an adequate protection is guaranteed for personal data to be transferred abroad. In some specific cases when this level of protection is not guaranteed, UEFA will obtain Your prior consent or establish with the recipient of personal data a contractual framework or sufficient safeguards that ensure an adequate level of protection abroad.

As part of its internal data auditing process, UEFA may conduct regular checks on processing by third parties, especially with respect to security measures.

 **Data Retention and Archiving**  
UEFA does not, as a matter of business practice, retain personal data longer than necessary for the purposes stated and to comply with legal requirements, unless otherwise agreed to by You. In particular, as soon as possible after the termination of Your relationship with UEFA, personal data will be deleted by UEFA unless UEFA has any legal obligation to retain the record.

 **Your Right to Access your Information**  
You have the right to request information on personal data related to You which are processed by UEFA. All request should be sent by regular mail along with a proof of identity (copy of official Identification Document with a photo mentioning Your date & place of birth), mention of the UEFA Platform’s URL and Your contact details (phone number and email) to:

Union des Associations Européennes de Football (UEFA)  
Corporate Legal Services  
Data Protection - Access Request  
Route de Genève 46  
Case postale,  
CH-1260 Nyon 2  
Switzerland

The request is free of charge unless You have already requested such information in the last twelve months or if the request generates a high workload to be answered by UEFA. In such case, UEFA may charge You a request fee according to applicable data protection legislation.

UEFA may refuse, restrict or defer the provision of information where UEFA has the right to do so under current data protection legislation.

 **Your Right to Update and Delete Your Information**  
You may request that inaccurate or incomplete personal data related to You be corrected or deleted where the purpose of data processing has lapsed or ceased to be applicable for other reasons.

To do so and unless otherwise specifically provided in Our Terms, You can either review, correct, update or delete Your information at any time by accessing Your account on the UEFA Platform where it has been created or, as alternative, You can send a formal request by mail along with a proof of identity (copy of official Identification Document with a photo mentioning Your date and place of birth), mention of the UEFA Platform’s URL and Your contact details (phone number and email) to:

Union des Associations Européennes de Football (UEFA)  
Corporate Legal Services  
Data Protection – Update / Delete Request  
Route de Genève 46  
Case postale,  
CH-1260 Nyon 2  
Switzerland

UEFA may refuse, restrict or defer Your request where UEFA has the right to do so under current data protection legislation.

 **Newsletters and Marketing Communications**  
Unsubscription from newsletters and e-mail marketing communications can most easily be done by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail newsletter We have sent to You or, alternatively, by modifying Your account settings and preferences.

 **Data Security**  
We want You to feel confident about using the UEFA Platforms. Therefore, UEFA defines and implements the reasonable technical and organizational measures necessary to maintain the security of personal data, according to the nature of the personal data processed and the circumstances of the processing, with the objective of avoiding (in the realm of the possible and having regard to the state of the art) non-authorised processing or access, alteration or loss (to ensure confidentiality, integrity and availability respectively).

In certain areas, UEFA uses industry standard SSL encryption to protect data transmissions. If You communicate with UEFA otherwise than via UEFA Platforms (e.g. by e-mail), You should however note that the secrecy of Internet is uncertain. By sending sensitive or confidential e-mail messages or information which are not encrypted, You accept the risk of such uncertainty and possible lack of confidentiality over the Internet.

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to UEFA. Safeguarding information to help protect You from identity theft is a great concern. UEFA do not and will not, at any time, request Your credit card information, Your account ID, login password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.

 **Cookies**  
UEFA may set and access its own cookies on Your computer. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to Your browser from a website's server and stored on Your computer's hard drive. By using UEFA Platforms, You consent to the above use of cookies.

UEFA uses its own cookies for number of purposes, mainly to:

• access Your information when You "sign in", so that we can provide You with customized content;  
• keep track of preferences You specify while You are using Services;

• collect information about your browsing habits when you don’t “sign in”;  
• estimate and report our total audience size and traffic;  
• conduct research and development to improve UEFA Content and Services and achieve and maintain a high service level.

UEFA may allow third parties to set and access their own cookies on Your computer. Third parties' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy statements and not this one. Please refer specifically to each third party website and privacy statements to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal information through their cookies. UEFA disclaims any liability in this respect.

For more information, please refer to the [Cookie Information](http://www.uefa.com/cookiepolicy/index.html).

 **Profiling  
** We may use the information you provide to us to better understand your interests so we can try to predict what other products, services and information you might be most interested in. We call this profiling.  This enables us to tailor our communications and those of our third parties to make them more relevant and interesting for you.  If you don’t want us to do this you may opt-out here <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>, or <http://www.aboutads.info/> or, for EU users only here: <http://youronlinechoices.eu/>. 

 **Children's Privacy**  
The protection of personal data of children and adolescents is of particular concern to UEFA. The UEFA Platforms and their content are not directed at children under the age of 13. UEFA recommends that parents discuss the use of the Internet and the provision of information on websites with their children before allowing minors between thirteen (13) and eighteen (18) to register.

UEFA will not knowingly collect personal data from or about children under thirteen (13) or minors between thirteen (13) and eighteen (18) without parental permission or knowingly allow such persons to register as Users. If a parent or legal guardian becomes aware that his or her child under eighteen (18) has provided UEFA with personal data without their consent, he or she should delete the account. If UEFA becomes aware that a child under thirteen (13) or between thirteen (13) and eighteen (18) but without parental permission has provided UEFA with personal data, that information will be deleted as quickly as possible and the access as a User immediately denied.

If You believe that UEFA might have any information from or about a child under thirteen (13), please send by mail Your request to Union des Associations Européennes de Football – Corporate Legal Services - Data Protection, Route de Genève 46, Case postale, CH-1260 Nyon 2, Switzerland. All request should be sent along with a proof of identity (copy of official Identification Document with a photo mentioning the date & place of birth of the child), the UEFA Platform’s URL and Your contact details (phone number and email).

 **Links to Other Sites**  
If any part of the UEFA Platforms link to other websites, those websites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. If You choose to visit an advertiser or click on another third party link, You will be directed to that third party’s website. We do not exercise control over third party websites and therefore recommend You examine the privacy statements posted on these other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal information.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
The Privacy Policy is available at any time through the UEFA Platforms and may be amended from time to time. We shall place an updated version on this page of the UEFA Websites. The UEFA Websites and/or the UEFA Apps may also provide notices of changes to this Privacy Policy or other matters by displaying notices or links to notices to You generally on or within the UEFA Platforms.

UEFA reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice to You. You are therefore responsible for regularly reviewing this Privacy Policy.

 **Jurisdiction and Applicable Law**  
This Privacy Policy and all matters arising out of or related to this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the substantive laws of Switzerland, without regards to conflicts of laws and principles thereof.

Any controversy, claim or dispute between You and UEFA arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of Nyon, Switzerland, and each party hereby irrevocably consents to the jurisdiction and venue of such Court.

©UEFA.com 1998-2015. All rights reserved.
